Rossario Catherine Elfrida

roselfridaa@gmail.com • github.com/catherineelfrida • linkedin.com/in/rossariocatherine • 62813-9831-4714 • Bekasi, Jawa Barat

Professional Summary

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical Engineering, specializing in Computer Engineering, graduated with honors (Sangat Memuaskan) from Udayana University. Skilled in software development, automation and team collaboration. Strong critical analysis, excellent focus, communication, and eargerness to learn new things. Experienced in building web-based applications using JavaScript in Agile environment. Interested in things related to backend, DevOps, and cloud computing.

Education

Udayana University, Bali (August 2019 - August 2024)

Bachelors of Engineering, Electrical Engineering

Cumulative GPA: 3.80/4.00

Relevant Coursework: Web-based Application Development, Object-oriented Programming, IoT, Software Engineering, AI, HCI, Databases, Data Structures, IT, Computer Networks.

Informal Educations

FGA 2023 - Cloud Automation with Ansible (June 2023 - September 2023)

- Graduated training program and currently preparing to take Red Hat Cloud Engineer Certification later this year.
- Enrolled in the Red Hat Enterprise Linux Automation with Ansible 9.0 (RH294) course.
- Learned to manage inventory, apply playbooks, configure variables and facts, apply control tasks, use the Jinja2 template, use roles and collections, troubleshoot Ansible, and automate Linux administrative tasks.

FGA 2023 – Backend Engineering Bootcamp (September 2023 – December 2023)

- Mastered JavaScript fundamentals and advanced concepts, as well as database management using PostgreSQL.
- Developed APIs using Node.js, Express.js, and Prisma, and implemented API documentation, testing, and security with authentication.
- Gained skills in media handling, deployment, debugging, WebSocket, and mailer integration.
- GitHub: https://github.com/catherineelfrida/Basic-Banking-System

FGA 2024 – Scalable Web Service with Golang (January 2024 – April 2024)

- Learned core Go programming fundamentals, including OOP, concurrency (Go-routines, channels), and API documentation.
- Developed scalable web services with microservices architecture, handling JSON/XML data, and integrating SQL & NoSQL databases.
- Enhanced skills in securing code, creating middleware, and conducting unit testing with Testify.
- GitHub: https://github.com/catherineelfrida/mygram-api

Experience

PT XL Axiata Tbk (August 2022 – December 2022)

DevOps Engineer Intern

- Provisioned 10+ cloud infrastructures with IaC tools.
- Automated deployment of 4 projects with CI/CD pipelines.
- Documented security status of 65 projects, maintained 20+ Git workflows.
- Identified areas for 15% overall improvement in team collaboration, monitoring and security.
- Supported migration of 10+ on-premises projects to the cloud.
- Analyzed cost efficiency of 100+ cloud projects, alerted team for anomalies/changes.

Fishku Indonesia (June 2022 – April 2023)

Software Engineer Apprentice

- A standout Bangkit project that received a \$10K award from Google and Kemendikbud.
- Played key role in 11-member team, developed seller and consumer app backends with full cloud integration.
- Streamlined development with Google Cloud Build and Repository, reducing deployment time by 70%.
- Ensured secure data management through Google Secret Manager for 5+ sensitive data items.
- Configured load balancers, maintaining 99.9% uptime and efficient traffic distribution.
- Optimized Google Cloud SQL databases, achieving 20% query response time reduction.
- Deployed machine learning models and Node.js backends on Google Cloud Run, 30% faster response times.
- Collaborated with Android developer, enhancing 100+ users' experiences.
- Enhanced security through Google's SLSA Build up to Level 3.
- Reduced cloud costs by 5% through monitoring and optimization.

Bangkit Academy 2022 (February 2022 – July 2022)

Cloud Computing Participant

- Mastered web development, GCP fundamentals, cloud-native app design in 21-member study group for 5 months.
- Earned 26 badges through Google Cloud Skill Boost program.
- Collaborated with 8-member team on machine learning and cloud-based capstone project.

Projects

JimbWash - Final Year Project (January 2023 – August 2024)

- Designed responsive mobile web app for laundry services with a team of 2.
- Integrated 10+ laundry marketplaces in Jimbaran.
- Implemented location-based services for 10+ nearest, cost-effective laundry providers
- Conducted usability tests, gathered insights from 30+ users for iterative enhancements.
- Completed with publication in SPEKTRUM, a SINTA 5 nationally accredited journal in Electrical Engineering.
- GitHub: https://github.com/catherineelfrida/marketplace-laundry-be
- Tech Stack: Node.js, Express.js, Prisma ORM, MySQL, Geocoding API, and responsive web design with Flexbox.

AQIMonitor (May 2022 – June 2022)

- Collaborated in team of 9 to develop Android app for air quality and weather warnings system.
- Scraped 1000+ data points using Node.js, utilized Express.js for client server communication.
- Top 2 teams out of 17+, chosen by Indosat Ooredoo Hutchison for Carbon Emissions and Waste Monitoring solutions.
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/catherineelfrida/company-capstone

Organizational Experience

IEEE Student Branch Universitas Udayana (January 2021 - January 2023)

- Managed finances as **Treasurer** in 2022, overseeing a budget of \$1000.
- Orchestrated ISCECE 2021 event as Master of Ceremonies, engaging 20+ participants and 15+ speakers.

Skills

- Programming: C++, C#, JavaScript, PHP, Java.
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL.
- Creating and architecting IT infrastructure with AWS/Google Cloud Platform services.
- Operating bash shell command line and tools in Linux.
- Using **Git** for effective version control and source code management.
- Create, run and manage containers with **Docker**.
- Using DevOps tools, such as Jenkins, Gitlab, Grafana, Dynatrace, Ansible.
- Implement server-side programming using Node.js, Express.js, Hapi.